Currently your update step for Policy Evaluation looks a bit like this.
目前 策略评估的更新步骤看起来差不多是这样
You generate an episode,
你生成一个阶段
then for each state-action pair that was visited,
然后对于经历的每个状态动作对
you calculate the corresponding return that follows.
你都计算接下来的相应回报
Then, you use that return to get an updated estimate.
然后使用该回报获得更新的估算
We're going to look at this update step a bit closer with the aim of improving it.
我们将进一步查看这个更新步骤 以便完善它
You can think of it as first calculating
你可以将其看做
the difference between the most recently sampled return,
首先计算最近取样的回报
and the corresponding value of the state-action pair.
和对应的状态动作对之间的差别
We denote that by Delta T,
我们用 δt 表示
and you can think of it as an error turn.
可以看做误差项
After all, it's the difference between what we expect the return to be,
因为它是我们期望的回报
and what the return actually was.
与实际回报之间的差
In the case that this error is positive,
如果该误差为正
well that means that the return that we
则表示我们收到的回报
received is more than what the value function expected.
比值函数预期的要大
In this case, the action value is too low,
在这种情况下 值函数太低
so we use this update step to increase the estimate.
我们使用这个更新步骤增大估值
On the other hand,
另一方面
if the error is negative,
如果误差为负
then that means that the return is higher than what the actual value function expected.
表示误差项比动作值函数预期的要高
So it makes sense to take into account this new evidence,
因此有必要考虑这个新的证据
and decrease the estimate and the actual value function.
并降低预期的动作值函数
And exactly how much do we increase or decrease the function?
到底要增大或降低该函数多少幅度呢？
Well currently, the algorithm decreases it by an amount inversely
目前该算法降低的量
proportional to the number of times that we've visited the state-action pair already.
与我们已经经历状态动作对的次数成反比
So the first few times we visit the pair,
因此前几次经历该对时
the change is likely to be quite large.
变化可能很大
But at future time points,
但是在后面的时间点
where the denominator of this fraction gets quite big,
当这个分数的分母变得很大时
the changes get smaller and smaller.
变化会越来越小
To understand why this would be the case,
要理解为何是这种情况
you have to remember that this equation just
你需要记住 这个方程式计算的是
calculates the average of all the sampled returns.
所有取样回报的平均值
So if you already have the average of 999 returns,
如果已经拥有 999 次回报的平均值
then when you take into account the 1,000th return,
当你考虑第 1000 次回报时
it's not going to change the average much.
将不会对平均值有多大的改变
So with this in mind,
记住这些信息后
we'll change the algorithm to instead use
我们将更改该算法
a constant step size which I've denoted by Alpha here.
并改用常量步长 表示为 α
This ensures that returns that come later are
这样可以确保稍后获得的回报
more emphasized than those that arrived earlier.
比之前获得的回报更受重视
In this way, the agent will mostly trust the most recent returns,
这样的话 智能体将最信任最新的回报
and gradually forget about those that came in the past.
并逐渐忘记先前获得的回报
This is quite important because remember that the policy is constantly changing,
这一点非常重要 因为该策略不断变化
and with every step becoming more optimal.
每一步都越来越优化
So in fact, later time steps are quite important to estimating the action values.
因此实际上 后面的时间步对估算动作值来说很重要
I strongly encourage you to make this amendment to
强烈建议你对你的蒙特卡洛策略评估算法
your algorithm for Monte Carlo policy evaluation.
进行这一修改